Mss.Rec.100 Mss.Rec.100
American Philosophical Society
Yavapai linguistic material
1973
Mss.Rec.100
American Philosophical Society
3.0 Reel(s)
Elicited Yavapai senteneces and word lists, including phonology and modals. Recorded in Arizona, June - July 1973.
3 sound tape reels (1 hr., 50 min.): analog, 3 3/4 ips, 2 track, mono.; 5 in.
Kendall, Martha Oaks (Burnett)
Sine, Harold
Related Archival Materials
Phonetic transcriptions and translations from the recording sessions are available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Martha Oaks Kendall in September 1974 (Acc. 1974 1164rec). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Hokan languages; Sound recordings; Yavapai language
- Audio recordings
  - Yavapai elicitation; The /k/ /m/ problem; Session #1, 1973-06-21; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:31; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Cottonwood (Ariz.); Yavapai language--Grammar; Yavapai language--Phonology; Yavapai language--Syntax
  - Yavapai elicitation; The /k/ /m/ problem; Session #2, 1973-06-22; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:49; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
  - Yavapai elicitation; The /k/ /m/ problem; Session #3, 1973-06-25; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:06; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
  - Hokan Word List; Session #1, 1973-06-26; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:56; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
    Cottonwood (Ariz.); Hokan languages; Yavapai language; Yavapai language--Grammar; Yavapai language--Syntax
  - Hokan Word List; Session #2, 1973-06-27; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:57; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
  - Hokan Word List; Session #3, 1973-06-28; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:14; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
  - Hokan Word List; Session #4, 1973-06-29; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:29; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
  - Yavapai Modals, Session #1, 1973-07-02; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:23; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
    Flagstaff (Ariz.); Yavapai language--Grammar; Yavapai language--Modality; Yavapai language--Syntax
  - Yavapai Modals, Session #2, 1973-07-02; 02-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:45; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
  - Yavapai Modals, Session #3, 1973-07-02; 02-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:20; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
  - Yavapai Elicitation Session #1, 1973-07; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:36; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold
    Scope and Contents note
    Recording consists of isolated phrases and sentences in Yavapai. Contents not specifically identified by collector.
    Arizona; Yavapai language--Grammar; Yavapai language--Syntax
  - Yavapai Elicitation Session #2, 1973-07; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:28; Kendall, Martha B.; Sine, Harold